Nagaraju Uppala

UI/UX & Product Designer

\subseteq	nagara	ju850109 ₀	@gmail.com
-------------	--------	-----------------------	------------

+1 (475) 287-6062

behance.net/nagaraju850770

An enthusiastic and driven user experience designer with more than two years of experience in branding, graphic design, and packaging. I'm looking for my next position in the web/app or product design industry where I can apply my design/UI/UX expertise to improve user experiences on mobile, tablet, and web-based devices.

EDUCATION

Touro University, New York.

MA (Web and Multimedia Design) Jan 2022 - Jan 2024

Backstage Pass Institute of Gaming and Technology

PGDM- Game Art and Design 2018 - 2019

Loyola Academy Degree & PG College

Degree- B.Sc. Animation Design 2015 - 2018

Narayana Junior College

Intermediate- MPC 2013 - 2015

SKILLS

Figma

Adobe Photoshop CC

Adobe Illustrator CC

Adobe InDesign CC

Adobe After effects CC

Adobe Premiere CC

Adobe Light room

Corel draw

Adobe XD

UI/UX Design

User Flows

Teamwork

Information Graphic

Package Design

Branding & Communications

Basic Html & CSS

EXPERIENCE

Mars by GHC

(May 2021 To December 2021)

PRODUCT DESIGNER.

- 1. Set design requirements based on information from internal teams and user research.
- 2. Use data collected from research, user testing, and market analysis to create truly User- centric designs
- 3. Illustrate and communicate complex design solutions across uses cases by creating process flows, wireframes, prototypes, and high-fidelity mock-ups.
- 4. Watch consumer trends to identify desirable product traits
- 5. Modify products in accordance with feedback from users and test groups.
- 6. Maintaining a design library for reference purposes
- 7. Sharing new design ideas and methodologies with management
- 8. Always keep an eye on the competitors and give better than them.

Kovida Itd

(OCT 2020 To 2021 MARCH)

ASSOCIATE GRAPHIC DESIGNER & STORYBOARD ARTIST.

- 1. Study design briefs and determine requirements
- 2. Conceptualize visuals based on requirements
- 3. Prepare rough drafts and present ideas
- 4.Develop illustrations, logos, and other designs using software or by hand
- 5. Use the appropriate colors and layouts for each graphic
- 6. Work with copywriters and creative director to produce the final design
- 7. Test graphics across various media
- 8. Amend designs after feedback
- 9. Ensure final graphics and layouts are visually appealing and on-brand

(OCT 2019 To 2020 OCT)

ASSOCIATE GRAPHIC DESIGNER.

- 1. Create and design various materials for print and digital collateral
- 2. Ensure projects are completed with high quality and on schedule
- 3. Establish creative direction for the company as well as brand guidelines
- 4. Prioritize and manage multiple projects within design specifications
- 5. Perform retouching and manipulation of images 6. Work with a wide range of media and use graphic design software

Strength:

- Ability to create and develop to sustain working relationship strong & self Dedication to succeed in creative professionalism.
- Positive thinking to plan and moves further.
- To achieve results with self-thought & patience.

Hobbies:

• Playing Chess • Like to explore new stuff. • Listening to Music

Achievements:

- Sports- I been titled District level player in Kabaddi.
- I've been elected as the Student Council member in my college to showcase my leadership qualities.
- Elected for Rotaract R.I District has-International service Director.